Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E.

[Electronics/Telecommunication]

Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

# Dayawan Sagar (1) Featured

Lead Consultant seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Product Management, Agile Methodology, Programming, ASP. Net MVC, JavaScript, Angularis, iQuery, Oracle, Ajax, VSTS, JIRA, TFS



Current Designation: Serving Notice period 24 days-- Lead

Consultant

Current Company: Genpact

Current Location: Pune

Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Agile Methodology, ASP. Net MVC, JavaScript, Angularjs, jQuery, Oracle, Ajax, VSTS, JIRA, TFS, Networking, . Net

Consultant, ASP.Net, javascript, C#.Net, C#., Net, SQL Server, VB.NET, WCF, Javascript, ADO.Net, LINQ, Entity

Framework,.NET Framework,API,Azure,TDD

Verified: Phone Number 1 Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

## Summary

7.5 years of IT industry experience encompassing a wide range of skill set, roles and industry verticals.

Extensive experience with analysis, design, development, customizations and implementation of software applications.

Proficient in analyzing and translating business requirements to technical requirements and architecture.

Strong database skills, Object Oriented Programming and development knowledge Experience in leading and managing teams as well

Executed software projects for Telecommunication, Airline, Manufacturing Industries

# Work Experience

Genpact as Serving Notice period 24 days-- Lead Consultant Mar 2020 to Till Date

since Mar 2020 and working for Client - Credit Suisse in Banking Domain since Jun 2020 .My role is as Individual contributor.

Environment: .Net Core, MVC ,Web API,C#, Angular 2 ,Typescript, SQL Server 2014,JIRA

#### Fiserv India Pvt Ltd as Software Development Engineer

Dec 2017 to Mar 2020

Product Name- Auto LOS

Automotive Loan Origination System is a comprehensive, end-to-end solution for automotive loan origination, from electronic application capture through efficient credit processing, funding verification, validation and booking of new loans and leases.

My role is as follows:

- Currently working on migrating the OLD Los application to Ignite Application With new UI and latest technology like asp.net core, web API and kendo Controls etc.
- Following the agile methodology and delivering the continuous product and code changes.
- Development and bug fixing in the existing application.

Environment: .Net Core ,Web API, JQuery, Java script, SQL Server 2014,TFS,Knedo Controls,Visual Studio 2017 & 2019 Team Size - 10

Product Name- Bill Matrix Next

Application provides ability to process Immediate and schedule payment. Form Post and SSO capability also provided so that biller can integrate application on their parent site.

Application has two views consumer UI and Admin UI using which user can schedule payment for frequencies via on due date, when bill arrives.

My role is as follows:

- Responsible for effective communication between the project team and the Product . Provide day to day direction to the project team and regular project status to the Product.
- Establish Quality Procedure for the team and continuously monitor and audit to ensure team meets quality goals.

Environment: ASP.NET, MVC ,Web API,C#, JQuery, Java script, SQL Server 2014,TFS,VSTS

Team Size - 10

#### IBM India Pvt Ltd as Application Developer

Jul 2012 to Dec 2017

Client Name- Johnson Controls Inc.

Many dot net Applications were in JCI such as SSR, Web SSR, Provider portal, Visual Scheduler etc. we have migrated these dot net applications from JCI to CBRE.

Apart from this, we have developed some applications like Gear, Online Admin, Online Admin-FMP Data Extract tool. My role is as follows:

- Requirement analysis, system design, coding/development, deployment.
- Coordinate and communicate tasks with developers
- Ensure that development is performed as per requirements
- Implemented new technologies such as Web API, Angular JS

Environment: C# .Net , VB.Net, MVC ,Angular JS ,Oracle 11g, Entity Framework

Team Size - 6

Client Name- Welspun India Pvt Ltd

As an Team Lead responsible for Analysis, design, development, testing and implementation of custom Applications. One of the key resource in the transition of the project from HP to IBM. My role is as follows:

- Deliver new and complex high quality solutions to clients in response to varying business requirements
- Translate customer requirements into formal requirements and design documents, establish specific solutions, and leading the efforts including programming and testing that culminate in client acceptance of the results.

Environment: C#.Net , VB.Net, SharePoint . Oracle 11g , ADO.Net

Team Size - 3

Client Name- Etihad Airways

IBM provides the services to Etihad Airways like Airport Operations, Revenue, Management, Flight Operations etc.. My role is as follows:

- Analysis of Business requirements.
- Designed new SSIS packages and new UI for existing applications
- Brought new technology to increase performance of existing application (new technology like Ajax, Jquery, Angular JS)
- Coordinate and communicate tasks with developers
- Ensure that development is performed as per requirements
- Developed the business logic using C#.NET, SSIS in middle tier and data tier.
- Communicate activities/progress to project managers, business development, business analysts and clients
- Debugging and fixing bugs.

Environment: C# .Net , VB.Net , Sharepoint , Angular JS , SSIS , Oracle 11g , ADO.Net

Team Size - 2

Client Name- Vodafone India Pvt Ltd

This application is made for Vodafone help desk. Vodafone works in many applications. They use this system to properly manage the various tasks related to those systems. In Vodafone counterparts there are two groups one is user and another is help desk admin. User group forward the application related issue or any new requirement to help desk admin. Admin member analyze the request and set the request category and forward the request to manager group of that application in IBM counterpart. Application development manager group takes the appropriate action and finally resolve and close the tasks. My role is as follows:

- Analysis of Business requirements.
- Requirement analysis, system design, coding/development, deployment.
- Responsible for designing database.
- Coordinate and communicate tasks with developers
- Ensure that development is performed as per requirements
- Implemented new technologies such as Ajax and Web Services.

Responsible for managing scope, planning, tracking, change control, aspects of the project

Environment: C#.Net, VB.Net, Oracle 11g,, ADO.Net, AJAX, Jquery, Javascript, Web Services, WCF, SQL

Team Size- 6

References: Available upon request

## **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from pune institute of computer technology in 2012

### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
Net Core 2.2	2.2	2020	2 Year(s) 3 Month(s)	
ASP.Net MVC	5	2019	2 Year(s) 4 Month(s)	
JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, AJAX, ANGULAR JS				
ORACLE 11G			2 Year(s)	
TFS		2019	1 Year(s)	
.Net Core	2.2	2020	2 Year(s) 3 Month(s)	
Angular 4	4	2020	1 Year(s)	
SQL		2020	2 Year(s)	
Entity Framework		2020	1 Year(s)	
API		2020	2 Year(s) 3 Month(s)	

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Marathi				

### **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No

### **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time